Guide to the Bernard Augustine De Voto Papers, 1918-1955 (inclusive), 1944-1951 (bulk) M0001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Research Material, Series 5
  - Miscellany, Subseries 5.5
    - U.S. Presidents - notes (Box 76.2, Folder 7)
    - Whiskey (Box 76.2, Folder 8)
    - Unclassified Notes (Box 76.2, Folder 9)
    - Research Notes and Material, misc. references on cards and small sheets of paper--mostly on history and relig. of Mormons, rattlesnakes; Newspapers in Philadelphia 1835-45, material copied by Florian DeVoto and sent to BDV--migration of Mormons incl. copy (hand drawn) of map showing pioneer trails in area of Salt Lake, etc. (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Printed Matter - General, Subseries 5.6
    Includes scrapbooks and clippings chronologically arranged by decades. Some of these are in folders; the folders include references to Bernard DeVoto, subjects such as conservation, politics, etc., reviews of his books; and articles and stories.
    - Clippings 1920's - 50's and Obituaries, 2 foot (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Articles and reviews (Box 154, Folder 2)
    - Articles by, referring to, annotated by or collected by B. Devoto, 2 foot Printed Matter (Box 155)
  - Printed Matter - Conservation, Subseries 5.7
    - Articles by, referring to, annotated by or collected by B. DeVoto, Memo By B.F. Heintzleman, 1945-1949 (Box 76.3, Folder 1)
    - Appendix No.1 and 2, Sevier Lake Watershed, Utah, 1950 (Box 76.3, Folder 2)
    - Appendix No.3 and 4, Sevier Lake Watershed, Utah, 1950- (Box 76.3, Folder 3)
    - Two U.S. Gov't Docs: Reports on power, 1952,1953; Reprints from Harper's Magazine (Box 76.3, Folder 4)
    - Articles by, referring to, annotated by or collected by B. DeVoto, no date (Box 76.3, Folder 5)
    - Five Gov't Docs: Hearings on Public Lands, Feb.10,1947-Sep. 2,1947 (Box 76.3, Folder 6)
    - Five Gov't Docs: Hearings on Public Lands, Sep.5, 1947-Sep. 22, 1947 (Box 76.3, Folder 7)
      26pp autograph notes included with hearings on Lake Crescent, Wash
  - Scrapbooks, Reviews of his Books, Subseries 5.8
    - Chariot of Fire (Box 77)
    - Crooked Mile (Box 77)
    - Mark Twain's America (Box 77)
    - Saturday Review (Box 77)
    - Easy Chair (Box 78)
    - Saturday Review (Box 78)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 79)
    - We Accept With Pleasure (Box 79)
    - Material not by DeVoto (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - MacLeish by C. Canby
      - Memorandum plea for more recognition of the West
      - Northwest Passage by L. Rohrbough
      - Psychiatry and Industry by L.S. Keeble
      - Review by R.G. Adams of "Puritan Oligarchy by T.J. Wertenbaker"
      - The South and our Country's Story by Herbert Ravanel Sass
    - Year of Decision 1846 (Box 164)
  - Miscellany, Subseries 5.9
    Includes photographs, awards, honors, etc. (See Container List).
    - Photos-Non-Personal, Sub-subseries 5.9.1
      - Flood Control Folder (Box 80, Folder 1)
        "Before and After" -- 3 volumes -- Envelope - 13 small snapshots -- 3 aerial vieews -- 1 map "Continental Hydrology" -- small folder - 4 photos, New Mexico
      - Grand Teton National Park, 6 photos (Box 80, Folder 2)
      - Glacier National Park, 11 photos (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Boise National Forest, 20 photos (Box 80, Folder 4)
      - Forest Service Folder, 1940's-1950's (Box 80, Folder 5)
        mounted and labeled photos of reseeding (6 sheets) -- 2 mounted-forest 1909 & 1948 (31 photos) -- 6 green "grazing allotment analysis"
      - Forest Fire Folder, 10 miscellaneous photos (Box 80, Folder 6)
        "Fire Fighting Experiment, Priest River, Idaho, 1952-9 photos
      - Dinosaur Monument, 21 photos 2 clippings (Box 80, Folder 7)
      - Soil Erosion, 8 photos (Box 80, Folder 8)
        small folder
      - Yellowstone and Grand Canyon, 4 photos (Box 80, Folder 9)
      - Ansel Adams' photo book-Death Valley, 11 Unidentified photos (Box 80, Folder 10)
      - Unidentified photos (Box 80, Folder 11)
        11 New Mexico and Utah
    - Personal, Sub-subseries 5.9.2
      - Legal and other documents (Box 81, Folder 1)
        - Contract with Minton Balch & Co., May 24, 1924
        - Contract with Little Brown & Co., April 23, 1926
        - Contract with MacMillan Co., June 30, 1926
        - Contract with Mark Twain Co., 1932
        - Civil Action No. 7070 - Ralph J. Burns vs 20th Century-Fox Film Co., Feb. 27, 1948
        - Court of Appeals Case No.89NE2D863, Dec. 29, 1949; 3 copies
          Brief for above case
        - Cyril Clemens copyright register Class A No.50717.
        - Warranty Deed of Miccosukee Seminols Nation.
        - Civil action No. 1134BH - Julian M. Gerard vs. Walter Scott, A.M. Johnson, et al.
        - Memorandum from Viking Press.
        - The Society of American Historians - Publishers Foundation Program
      - Memberships, ID's. (Box 81, Folder 2)
        - Student Activity card - University of Utah, 1914-1915
          1914-1915.
        - Columbian National Life Insurance Co. - Change of Beneficiary from DeVoto's mother to his father, Nov. 8, 1919.
        - Card to Harvard Club -, Dec., 1919
        - American Legion Card, Dec., 1921
        - Membership Card: Society of Midland Authors, 1926
        - War Department Identification -, Nov., 5, 1943
        - Ancient Order of River Rats card -, Jan., 1948
        - General Tire Credit Card, 1952
        - The Waber Club, Ogden, Utah, May, 1952
        - American Forestry Association Card, March, 1953
        - Outdoor Writers Association of America, Membership, 1953
        - City of Seattle Courtesy Card, 1954
        - Missouri Historical Society Membership Card -, Aug., 1955
        - U.S. Dept. of Interior National Park Service Lifetime Pass #8., 1955
        - Card for Ecole des Gourmandes.
        - Sierra Club, San Francisco, Life-time Pass.
        - Strip place name - Bernard DeVoto
      - Small folder - 2 astronomical charts (Box 81, Folder 3)
      - Framed summons to [UNK] court for Strange Fruit case, April 12, 1944 (Box 81, Folder 4)
      - Limited Editions Club Silver Jubilee Awards, May 11, 1954 (Box 81, Folder 5)
        Program and award
      - Receipt: Central Hanover Bank & Trust Co. from B. DeVoto for all all manuscripts, papers and other material of Samuel L. [UNK] (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Business transactions with Houghton Mifflin (Box 81, Folder 7)
        - Business transactions with Little Brown, 1940-1947
- Photographs, Series 6
  - Family and Friends, Subseries 6.1
    - Florian DeVoto (father), framed. (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - DeVoto's boyhood (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Baby on bear rug.
      - (six months), June 16, 1897
      - (1 yr. 1 no.), February, 1898; 2 copies.
      - (2 yrs. 10 no.), November, 1898; 3 copies.
      - With two sisters, aged 10 years, n.d.; 3 copies.
      - 3 boyhood pictures, n.d.
      - 3 in military uniform, n.d.
    - 1 photo album of DeVoto as a child (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Dated DeVoto pictures-approximate dates given by Avis DeVoto. approx., 1934 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Pencil Drawing by Dwight Shaples, 1935
      - Group picture, Honorary Degree Northeastern University, October 2, 1948
      - Investiture at Northeastern Univ., October 2, 1948
      - Portland, Oregon, January 12, 1954
      - with Stewart Holbrook, January 12, 1954
      - with Stewart Holbrook in Erickson's saloon, January 12, 1954
      - In the 500
      - Group picture including Alfred Knopf Ad. Bd. National Parks, October 26, 1951
      - Columbia Broadcasting, 1955; 2 copies plus negative
        (copied February 1961) - DeVoto in his library
    - Undated DeVoto Photographs (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - With dean of a college in Hartford
      - With Katherine Porter
      - 2 pictures in flying gear for article on smoke Junipers
      - 2 pictures with President Stearns of Colorado Univ. (Norlin medal)
      - 5 proofs from Blackstone Studies, New York
      - 1 finished portrait of above
      - 2 sheets of film clips - Time Magazine
      - 2 undated snapshots
    - Photos. (Box 82, Folder 5)
      - Living room at Bread Loaf
      - With Fletcher Pratt
      - With A. B. Guthrie, Jr
      - With Pratt and Upson
      - With Mr. and Mrs. Mark Saxton
      - 2 group pictures
    - Pictures NOT of DeVoto (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - Private Gordon DeVoto, son of Bernard DeVoto, Feb. 9, 1955
      - Mr. and Mrs. Fletcher Pratt
      - Robert Jay
      - William Upson
      - Assorted Photographs, not in 1980
    - Framed Pictures (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - Lee Foster Hartman, Item 1
      - Kent Hagler, Item 2
      - Mark Twain - 1875, Item 3
      - Mark Twain - 1875, Item 4
      - Mark Twain - 1900, Item 5
      - Unframed Pictrues
      - William Dean Howells, Item 6
      - A. J. Miller - Self-portrait, Item 7
      - Fort Ticonderoga Bicentennial Medal, 1755-1955; Item 8
  - Photos - miscellaneous, Subseries 6.2
    New England, the West Literary figures.
    - Photographs - Gettysburg (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Photographs - Lincoln, Mass. (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Photographs - Literary figures (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Photographs - Monuments, New England (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Photographs - Motor trip, summer, 1938 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Photographs - N. Y. Miscellaneous, 1937 - 1938 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Photographs - Summer, 1937, Vermont and Martha's Vineyard (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Photographs - Vermont, miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Photographs - Hurrican in Walpole, N. H. (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Photographs - Walpole, N. H., summer, 1938 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Photographs - West, conservation (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Photographs - West, 1940 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Photographs - West, 1951 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Photographs - B. De Voto, youth (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Photographs - B. De Voto with friends, acquaintances, etc. (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Photographs - West, miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Photographs - Publicity (Box 85, Folder 18)
    - Photographs - Virginia City, Montana, Custer's Battlefield, West, misc. (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - Photographs - West, miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - Photographs - Boise forest (Box 85, Folder 21)
    - Photographs - Jackson Hole, Yellowstone, Sunlight (Box 85, Folder 22)
    - Photographs - California, Idaho and Idaho City (Box 85, Folder 23)
    - Photographs - Willamette and Glacier Park (Box 85, Folder 24)
    - Photographs - Miscellaneous national parks, many taken by Ansel Adams (Box 85, Folder 25)
- DeVoto Memorial and Plaque files, Series 7
  - Corresp. chron. to DeVoto Memorial; Robert Sykes, pres. Montana Wildlife Federation; Mrs. DeVoto., Apr.-Dec., 1962 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Arthur Schlesinger Jr. to ADV with John A. Carvers Jr.--address on BVD, Apr; 2 T.L.S.
    - (verifax) Lawrence D. Rockefeller to Lee Metcalf (note by Metcalf), Jul 26; 2 copies
    - Tim Babcock (Gov. Montana) regrets, Aug; 2 T.L.S.
    - Mr. [Berder] regrets, Aug; 6 A.N.S.
    - Annie Laurie Bird (Idaho D.A.R.) regrets, Aug; 6 T.L.S.
    - Arthur Hawthorne Carhart regrets, Aug; 6 T.L.S.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Paul Cushing Child regrets, Aug; 6 A.L.S.
    - Orville L. Freeman (Sec. Agric.) regrets, Aug; 6 T.N.S.
    - Kenneth Fowell (Dir. Ft. Falls Mont. Recreation Dept.) regrets, Aug; 6 T.N.S.
    - V. L. Harper (Asst. Chief U.S. Forest Service) regrets, Aug; 6 T.N.S.
    - J. C. Kieffer (pres. Idaho Mining Assn) regrets, Aug; 6 T.N.S.
    - Alfred A. Knopf (publisher) regrets, Aug; 6 T.N.S.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Theodore Morrison regrets, Aug; 6 A.N.S.
    - Frank E. Moss (U.S. Sen.-Utah) regrets, Aug; 6 A.N.S.
    - Rogert E. Smylie (Gov. Idaho) regrets, Aug; 6 T.N.
    - Ralph S. Space (Forest Supervisor Clearwater Nat'l Forest) accept., Aug; 6 T.N.S.
    - Ernie L. Wales regrets, Aug; 6 T.L.S.
    - Frank Church (U.S. Sen. Idaho) regrets, Aug; 7 T.N.S.
    - H. H. Hanson (pres. Orofino Idaho C of C) regrets, Aug; 7 T.N.S.
    - Floyd Iverson (Region'l Forester Intermtn.) accept, Aug; 7 T.N.S.
    - W. J. Lederer (s. by sec.) regrets, Aug; 7 T.N.
    - [H. A.] Laughlin of Houghto-Mifflin (s. by sec., 7 T.N.
    - Mike Mansfield (U.S. Sen. Mont.) regrets, Aug; 7 T.N.S.
    - Catherine Meyer (Harper's Mag.) regrets, Aug; 7 T.N.S.
    - Joseph F. Pechanec (Dir. Intermtn. Forest & Range Experimt. Sta.-Ogden) regrets, Aug; 7 T.N.S.
    - Louise Shadduck (Exec. Sec. Idaho) regrets, Aug; 7 T.N.S.
    - John T. Edsall regrets, Aug; 8 A.N.S.
    - Ralph R. Harding (U.S. Rep. Idaho) regrets, Aug; 8 T.N.S.
    - [I.] H. Harris (pres. Idaho St. C of C) regrets, Aug; 8 T.N.S.
    - Glenn A. Kovar (Dir. Mont. Pic. Forest Ser) regrets, Aug; 8 T.N.S.
    - Wayne Morse (U.S. Sen. Ore.) regrets, Aug; 8 T.N.S.
    - Arnold Olsen (U.S. Rep. Mont.) regrets, Aug; 8 T.N.S.
    - McGeorge Bundy regrets, Aug 9; T.N.S.
    - Mike Mansfield regrets, Aug 9; (T.N.S.)
    - Wayne Morse regrets, Aug 9; T.N.S.
    - Ansell Adams (photographer) regrets, Aug 10; (T.N.S.)
    - Emily M. Beck regrets, Aug 10; A.N.S.
    - Paul Brooks (Houghton-Mifflin) regrets, Aug 10; T.N.S.
    - Frank Church regrets, Aug 10; T.N.S.
    - Carvel Collins (Eng. Prof.) regrets, Aug 10; A.N.S.
    - Paul H. Douglas (U. S. Sen. Ill.) regrets, Aug 10; T.N.S.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Walter D. Edmonds regrets, Aug 10; A.N.S.
    - Lawrence S. Kubie (M.D.) regrets, Aug 10; T.N.S.
    - Mrs. Olans J. Munie regrets, Aug 10; Ap.c.S.
    - Adlai E. Stevenson (U.N. Rep.) regrets, Aug 10; T.N.S.
    - Ansell Adams, wants to make "really fine print" of BVD, Aug 11; T.L.S.
    - Rose Dely regrets, Aug 11; A.N.S.
    - [J. E. Morrison?] regrets, Aug 11; Ap.c.S.
    - James E. Battin (U.S. Rep. Mont.) regrets, Aug 13; T.N.S.
    - Sarah [Boyden] (Mrs. Wm. C.), Chicago Sun, regrets, Aug 13; T.N.S.
    - Paul Driscoll, Aug 13; T.N.S.
    - [UNK] Spaulding (Houghton-Mifflin, s. by sec.) regrets., Aug 13; T.N.
    - A. B. Curtis (Mayor of Orofino) regrets, Aug 14; T.N.
    - Arthur C. Deck (Exec. ed. Salt Lk. Trib.) regrets, Aug 14; T.N.S.
    - David McCord regrets, Aug 14; T.N.S.
    - N. J. Osborne (Sunshine Mining C. Spokane) regrets, Aug 14; T.N.S.
    - Clinton P. Anderson, s. by sec. (U.S. Sen., N. Mex.) regrets, Aug 14; T.N.
    - W. J. Everin (Dir. Mont. Fish & Game Cmm,) regrets, Aug 15; T.N.S.
    - George B. Amas (Gen. Tel. Com. Rel. Mgr.) regrets, Aug 16; T.N.S.
    - Harold P. Fabian (Nat'l Pk. Service, Wyo.) regrets, Aug 16; T.N.S.
    - John Fischer (Harper's Mag.) regrets, Aug 16; T.N.S.
    - Roger L. Guernsey (Idaho St. Forester) regrets, Aug 16; T.N.S.
    - Roland R. Renne (pres. Mont. St. Coll.) regrets, Aug 16; T.N.S.
    - Ernest Wohletz (dean forestry, U. of Id.)?, Aug 16; T.N.S.
    - K. A. Keeney (co-ordinator) to Gregory Rochlin with 8/13/62 Rochlin (treas.) regrets, Aug 17; A.N.S. carbon
    - Mrs. William L. Langer regrets, Aug 17; A.N.
    - John R. Milodragorich (Forest Service Nez Perce Nat'l Forest) accept, Aug 17; T.N.S.
    - Wallace Stegner (prof. & author) regrets, Aug 17; T.N.S.
    - Homer E. Martin (Boise Atty) regrets, Aug 20; T.N.S.
    - Chester J. Olsen (Ogden) concerning ADV's reservations, progress on Memorial & dedication, Aug 20; T.N.S.
    - and carbon, Edward C. Crafts (Dir. Bur. Outdoor Rec., Interior Dept., regret, Aug 21; T.N.S.
    - Paul D. Dalke by sec. (leader Idaho Co-op Wildlife Research Unit) regret, Aug 21; T.N.
    - Herb C. Jensen (Gen. Mgr. El Mirador, Palm Springs) to Lilliam Hernich, accept, Aug 22; T.N.S.
    - D. R. Theophilus (pres. U. of Idaho) regret, Aug 24; T.N.S.
    - W. R. White (Ogden mfgr) regret, Aug 24; T.N.S.
    - Crane Brinton (Harvard Prof. and historian) regrets, Aug 26; A.N.S.
    - Mrs. Lybe Johnsrud (Mont. Fed. Garden Clubs) regret, Aug 26; T.N.S.
    - George L. Nichols (Ogden) regret, Aug 27; T.N.S.
    - James C. Urguhart regret & prior acceptance, Aug 27; A.N.S.
    - Eveolaen N. Rexford (Cambridge, M.D.) regret, Aug 30; A.N.S.
    - Royce G. Cox (Porlatch Forests Inc.) regret, Aug 31; T.N.S.
    - Mrs. Vione Bell (Hubert J.) Mont. Fed. Womens Clubs) accept, Sept. 1; T.N.S.
    - Henry Dart Reck regret, Sept. 3; A.N.S.
    - Fred Scriven (Ogden) regret, Sept. 2; A.N.S.
    - Don F. Valiton (Nat'l Assn. Postmaster's v-p Desr Lodge) regret, Sept. 4; T.N.S.
    - A. L. Glasmann (Ogden Standard Examiner) regret, Sept. 5; T.N.S.
    - John F. Kennedy (U.S. Pres.) to Mr. Sykes concerning dedication and BVD, Sept. 5; T.L.S.
    - Maurine B. Neuberger (U.S. Sen. Ore.) regret, Sept. 5; T.L.S.
    - Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. repeats JFK's letter, Sept. 6; Tel.
    - James K. Vessey to ADV regret, Sept. 6; A.L.S.
    - and carbon, James K. Vessey to C. J. Olsen, letter to be read at dedication, Sept. 6; T.L.S.
    - Clint Davis (for chief of Forest Service), his remarks for dedication, Sept. 7; Tel.
    - Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. regret and message, Sept. 7; Tel.
    - Wayne Montgomery, regret and message, Sept. 8; Tel.
    - Ptd. invit. to dedication from Mont. & Idaho Wildlife Fed., Albert N. Cochrell varso regret, Sept. [9]; A.N.S.
    - df. of speech, Chas. H. Callison, dedication typescript with ms. corrections, Sept. 9
    - Herbert Scheinberg regret, Sept. 9; Tel.
    - William F. Johnston (mg. ed. Lewiston Morning Trib.), story of dedication, Sept. 11; T.N.S.
    - Edward P. Cliff (chief U.S. Forest Service), Sept. 12; T.L.S.
    - "Sarah" [Boyden] (Chicago) A.P. story, pers., Sept. 14; T.L.S.
    - copy [ADV] to [J. F. Kennedy], Sept. 15; T.L.
    - Maurine B. Neuberger, re: ceremony, Swedon, Sept. 24; T.L.S.
    - Arthur Schlesinger, Jr. pers., Sept. 24; T.L.S.
    - "Charlie" (Nat'l Audubon Soc.) wants to do vol. of BVD's consarvation essays, Wilderness Bill, Oct. 16; A.L.S.
    - Gregory Rochlin, residual of memorial fund, Nov. 21; T.L.S.
    - K. A. Keeney (Missoula) album of Grove, Dec. 3; T.L.S.
    - Lilliam Hornick album of Grove and carbon to Keensy, Dec. 3; T.L.S.
    - Gregory Rochlin, Dec. 11; T.L.S.
    - Mrs. Anne Nagel Barrett, regret, n.d.; A.N.S.
    - Catherine Drinker Bower (author) regret, n.d.; A.N.S.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Jerome Seymour Bruner regret, A.N.S.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Wilbur K. Jordan regret, A.N.S.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Sargent Kennedy regret, A.N.S.
    - Adelaide McClelland regret, A.N.S.
    - Marie Marshall (pres. Idaho Fed. Garden Clubs) regret, n.d.; A.N.S.
    - Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Ballard Murdock regret, A.N.S.
    - Arnold Olsen (U.S. Rep. Mont.) regret, n.d.; T.N.
    - Mrs. Charles Winkber (pres. I.F.W.C.) regret, n.d.; T.N.S.
  - DeVoto Memorial--clips, 1962 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    program, clips on dedication, obit. of Chester Olsen
  - Sawey Correspondence, 1965-66 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    Corresp. between Orlan Saway, ADV, Anne N. Barrett of Houghton-Mifflin, Jay Williams of Little, Brown, & Co., Harry P. Rowe, R. E. Monros, some duplicates and copies
  - Sawey Manuscript, Bernard DeVoto, carbon of third draft--critical study of DeVoto's development as a writer and common element of major works (American West) (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - The Margery Case, 1924-25 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    typescript and published accounts of seances of the medium Margery. Material by or collected by Robert Hillyer. Copies of The Banner of Life
  - Reviews of DeVoto's Work, 1926-28 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    clips, typescript, The Chariot of Fire, BVD's criticism of educ., The House of Sun-Goss-Down
  - Reviews by BDV, 1927 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    clips--T. M. Longstreth's The Silent Force -- H. Speakman's Mostly Mississippi -- L. Saxon's Father Mississippi -- P. A. Rollins Jinglebob -- Scherer's The First Forty-Niner -- A. E. Newton's The Greatest Book in the World -- A. Black's American Husbands -- B. Russell's What I Believe -- W. N. Burus's Tombstone -- B. B. Lindsey and W. Evans's The Companionate Marriage.
  - MacVicar, Helen Avis--Eng. Themes, Mrs. DeVoto's outlines and themes for Eng. class at Northwestern taught by BDV, some typescript, some ms. Ms. notes and corrections by BDV in pencil, corrections by ADV in red; there are long criticisms and questions by BDV on many of them, most with replies by ADV; some ms. themes of other members of the class-- some corrected with comments, a few by foreign students. (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, On Utah, Utah history, Mormons, Mormonism, and one on the 49'rs. (Box 83, Folder 5)
- DeVoto Memorial and Plaque files, Series 8
  - Miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Eugene Manlove Rhodes--mss. sent to BDV--an article and a poem, both rejected
    - The Curry Powder Mystery"--clippings, 4/27/48; T.L.S.
    - Fletcher Pratt to ADV, 5/27/48
    - George Horne to Bernard De Voto, T.L.S.
    - The Coolidge Hill Gazette -- Vol. 1 No. 3, [1954]; (2 copies)
      mimeographed newsletter, with previously unpublished poems by Robert Frost, Robert Hillyer, and [?]
    - The Bishop's Lament", galley of 1885 anti-Mormon poem
    - 1888 Warranty Deed--sale of land in Weber Co. Utah.
      George Edward and Matilda Cross to Sarah J. White
    - 1919 Deed to cemetary plot. City of Ogden to Florian B. DeVoto
    - Bulletin of the Carnegie Free Library, Ogden, Vol.2, No. 1., April, n.d.
      article on BDV. Also two road maps, one of Idaho, one of Wyoming.